A Guide to the Harry Harris Collection of Miscellaneous Virginia Manuscripts, 1759-1865
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Collection of Miscellaneous Virginia Manuscripts, 1759-1869
Library of Virginia
19875
1 folder (24 items)
Harry Harris
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Harry Harris of Richmond, Virginia, on 2 February 1927.
Biographical Information
Harry Harris was a book dealer, merchant, and resident of Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Contains various Virginia-related documents, mostly court records, from the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Items principally relate to Halifax County, Virginia, and include appointments and commissions for notary publics and justices of the peace issued by governors of Virginia. There are also letters concerning justices of the peace, the Revenue Tax of 1793, and acts of the General Assembly regarding slaves and pensioners. Virginia Governors include John B. Floyd, John Tyler, James Monroe, James B. Preston, Frances H. Pierpont, John Page, Henry A. Wise, Joseph Johnson, and John Letcher. Other notable subjects are Beverly Barksdale, William Ceaser, Robert Gayle, James D. Hankins, Henry L. Hines, George C. Holt, Ezekiel Jacob, Samuel Jacob, James A. King, James Lawson, James S. Lovelace, John A. McCraw, Samuel P. Moore, Charles Scott, John B. Scott, John Sims, William H. Sims, and Thomas Tarpley.
Arrangement
Chronological
Contents List
- Order of court-martial, Louisa County, by Thomas Perkins, Clerk, 27 September 1759, a; 1 p. Ms.; The court-martial concerned Samuel Ray who had failed to appear at a muster called by Captain David Mills
- Partial circular letter from Virginia Governor Edmund Randolph to the Justices of Halifax County, 20 May 1788, b; 1 p., printed; This letter calls attention to various acts relevant to pensioners.
- Circular letter from John Pendleton at the State Auditor's Office in Richmond, Virginia, to the Clerk of Halifax County, 1 October 1794, c; 1 p., printed form filled in; The letter, which is signed by Pendleton, concerns collection of the "Revenue Tax of 1793."
- Deed from Ezekiel Jacob of Prince George County, Maryland, to Samuel Jacob of Anne Rundel County, Maryland, for 300 acres of land in Monongalia County, Virginia, 24 March 1796, d; 2 pp. Ms.; Recorded in Monongalia County Deed Book, No. 1, page 28.
- Circular letter from Virginia Governor James Monroe in Richmond, Virginia, to the Halifax County Court, 16 April 1802, e; 1 p., printed; In this letter Monroe calls attention to an act of assembly relative to slaves.
- Appointments issued to Robert Terry and John Wilson as justices of the peace in Halifax County by Virginia Governor John Page, 20 August 1803, f; 1 p., printed form filled in; The reverse side notes the men qualified in September 1803.
- Circular letter from Virginia Governor John Page to the Clerk of Halifax County, 17 October 1803, g; 1 p., printed; In the letter John Page comments on an act of assembly concerning slaves, free blacks, and mulattoes.
- Letter from Virginia Governor John Page to the Clerk of Halifax County, 25 January 1805, h; 1 p. Ms.; In the letter Page replies to an inquiry concerning the appointment of justices of the peace.
- Appointments issued to Charles Scott, John Sims, George Smith, and James Lawson as justices of the peace for Halifax County by Virginia Governor John Tyler, 21 September 1810, i; 1 p., printed form filled in; On verso there is a note that John Sims qualified in October 1810 and Charles Scott qualified in February 1812.
- Appointment issued to Robert Gayle as inspector of tobacco at Bentleyville Warehouse in Halifax County by Virginia Governor James Preston, 19 March 1819, j; 1 p., printed form filled in
- Appointments issued to John B. Scott, John A. McCraw, William H. Sims, Beverly Barksdale, Thomas Tarpley, and David Tuck as justices of the peace for Halifax County by Virginia Governor John B. Floyd, 12 January 1849, k; 1 p., printed form filled in; On verso there is a note that all of the men qualified on 22 January 1849.
- Democratic ticket for the 1852 presidential election, l; 1 p., printed; The ticket lists Franklin Pierce, William R. King, and the Democratic electors from Virginia.
- Appointment issued to James S. Lovelace as notary public in Halifax County by Virginia Governor Joseph Johnson, 22 December 1852, m; 1 p., printed form filled in; On verso there is a note that Lovelace qualified on 24 January 1853.
- Commission issued to John A. McCraw as justice of the peace for Halifax County by Virginia Governor Henry A. Wise, 27 June 1858, n; 1 p., printed form filled in; The vacancy was caused by the resignation of McHainey Hubbard.
- Certificate of registration issued to William Ceaser, a free black man in Halifax County, by William S. Holt, Clerk of Court, [186-], o; 1 p. Ms.; This document includes the seal of the Halifax County court.
- Commissions issued to Littleton Edmunds, C. C. Anderson, James D. Hankins, and E. A. Coleman as justices of the peace for Halifax County by Virginia Governor John Letcher, 2 August 1860, p; 1 p., printed form filled in
- Certificate (No. 4103) issued to E. C. Elmore, Treasurer of the Confederate States of America, by the Confederate States of America through C. T. Jones, Acting Register of the Treasury, 26 August 1862, q; 1 p. Ms.; This certificate for $500 was issued by the C. S. A. under the act dated 24 December 1861.
- Commission issued to James A. King as justice of the peace for Halifax County by Virginia Governor John Letcher, 28 October 1862, r; 1 p., printed form filled in; The vacancy was caused by the death of John C. Gregory.
- Letter from Samuel P. Moore, Surgeon General of the Confederate States of America, in Richmond, Virginia, to Henry L. Hines, First North Carolina Hospital, Petersburg, Virginia, 3 December 1862, s; 1 p., printed form filled in; Notice that the Army Medical Board has made a favorable report in this case. It appears that Hines had been examined by the Board relevant to approval as a surgeon.
- Letter from A. Butts Jr., in Petersburg, Virginia, to Henry L. Hines, surgeon in charge of the South Carolina Hospital, 30 July 1863, t; 1 p. Ms.; In the letter Butts recommends Mrs. Yates M. Browne for appointment as matron in the hospital.
- Special Order No. 189, from the Medical Director's Office issued by William A. Carrington, Medical Director of Hospitals in Virginia, 11 November 1863, u; 1 p., printed form filled in; Assistant Surgeon Henry L. Hines is relieved from duty at the South Carolina Hospital in Petersburg and ordered to report to Surgeon J. L. Cabell in charge of the hospital in Charlottesville. On verso is a notation that Hines reported for duty on 19 November 1863.
- Appointment issued to George C. Holt as notary public for Halifax County by Virginia Governor Francis H. Pierpont, 11 August 1865, v; 1 p., printed form filled in
- Letter from R. B. Tuck to the Office of the Military Command of the District of Virginia, 30 September 1869, w; 1 p. Ms.; This is a note written by Tuck on a printed form titled, "Oath Prescribed by Act of 2 July 1862." It appears that Tuck had been appointed or elected to an office and was sent the form to complete whereby he pledged to support the United States Constitution. Tuck did not complete the form but wrote that he had subscribed to the oath when he entered the office of constable and did not believe it necessary to do so again. On verso there is a notation by Captain Edward Collins requesting the clerk of Halifax County return the form and advise if the oath taken by Tuck is on file in the county.
- Writ of summons to appear in Halifax County court, n. d., x; 2 pp., printed form; Blank forms that have not been completed. They designate Paul Carrington as clerk of the county. He served from 1773-1776. Also list of Isaac Cole's titheables for 1777